Alan White

5 St David's Court, Dalgety Bay, KY11 9SU Telephone: 07595 372 886 Email: info@monkeymake.xyz http://www.linkedin.com/in/alanwhite

Personal Statement

I'm an experienced, passionate and talented front-end web developer specialising in Web Standards and Accessibility with a strong attention to detail and a good eye for design. With 17 years commercial experience in web development I have covered many bases and under many circumstances which include working inhouse for an online shop, freelance CMS development, on site contracting, running my own conference and also in an agency environment working with blue chip clients. I have also organise and have spoken at web events and also universities.

Key Skills

Keen awareness of industry trends, standards compliant code, accessibility auditing, good client facing skills, good understanding of user requirements, good at developing new ideas, ability to carry a project from concept to completion. HTML5, CSS, SASS, LESS, BEM, JavaScript, JQuery, Handlebars, Patternlab. Currently trying to learn more about React and also Vue.js so I can integrate with modern JS frameworks more efficiently.

Experience

Sep 2017 - Present: Chairman - Web Matters - The industry body for the web in the UK

Web Matters is a new, independent, member-driven industry association for those who create and work on the open web. I have been a key stakeholder in taking this from concept to now having an active membership whom we represent. Currently sitting as Chairperson and active in the steering committee.

Dec 2015 - Present: Web Consultant & Maker of Things - Monkey Make Ltd

Independent web consultant working for various clients, my primary focus is on improving front end development practises alongside developing scalable interfaces and pattern libraries. Regularly sub contracting doing front end development for clients and also doing some work in the 3D Printing/Maker space.

Apr 2015 - Nov 1015 - Contract Front End Developer - Realise

Front development role focussing on delivery of front end templates for CMS integration.

Nov 2014 - Mar 2015: Contract Front End Developer - G2G3

Worked within a multi discipline team creating accessible HTML prototypes with sprinklings of SVG and JavaScript. Under NDA I can't disclose further information about the project.

Feb 2014 - Oct 2014: Contract Front End Developer - Tesco Bank

Worked on prototyping and developing a key internal project in an agile environment. Technologies included

HTML/Handlebars, SASS and Assemble for front end build and Grunt for automation of build. Also completed an agile workshop whilst on site. Further work includes implementing automating front end regression tests with tools such as Wraith and Phantom CSS and providing a roadmap for the future.

2007 – Present: Founder and Organiser - The Highland Fling - Web Standards in Scotland

The Highland Fling is a one day conference held in Edinburgh and aimed at helping raise the profile of web development in Scotland and to act as a platform for educating people. Focussing on edgy yet practical topics, the conference provides access to some of the leaders and thinkers of the web industry.

October 2012 - Jan 2014: Contract Front End Developer - Wood Mackenzie

Front end development role involving rapid development of HTML prototypes based on a heavily themed and extended version of Bootstrap. Key responsibilities have been HTML/CSS and parts of the Javascript implementation, rapid development of HTML fragments for integration by an offshore development team and also liaising with the UX team over ad-hoc changes to functionality. CodeIgniter was used for templating and Grunt was used for the asset pipeline / build process.

August 2011 - October 2012: Platform/UI Developer - Iplay

A senior front end developer role, responsible for the front end code base of a white label games delivery platform. I made performance enhancements to the front end and introduced new prototyping methodologies and technologies to the team. Features were developed on a 2 week release cycle using SCRUM and CI. Also worked on their game launcher which was based on a custom themed Bootstrap installation and Backbone.js, all delivered in an embeddable HTML5 environment on CD or via digital download.

June 2008 – August 2011: Interface Developer - Tesco Bank

Responsible for the Tesco Bank front end code base, developing standards and practices and constantly looking for ways to improve the end user experience. My primary role over the final year there was as a key stakeholder in moving away from RBS as a technology platform to Tesco Bank architecture. I have was involved in all aspects of development from the technical side of things right through to the front end code and the details of how the CMS functions.

August 2006 – February 2011: Web Developer & Consultant - Alan White Web Development

Acting as a sole trader I provided freelance services to agencies as well as providing web development services to an existing client base. The majority of the work I did was front end template development, I also provided bespoke blog and content management solutions. Key Clients: Headscape, Stuff & Nonsense, LBi, Mackerel Media.

- May 2008 June 2008 (2 months): Contract Interface Developer LBi
- December 2006 February 2007 (3 months): Contract Web Developer Xansa Resourcing
- May 2006 June 2006 (2 months): Contract Web Developer DC Interact

Feb 2005 – April 2006: Web Developer – DC Interact, Edinburgh.

This role involved working closely with stakeholders to help realise complex and challenging designs for key

clients such as Tesco, Norwich Union, Clydesdale Bank, Glenfiddich, Scottish Power and Littlewoods. As well as managing the development of accessible templates using standards compliant (X)HTML & CSS, I was responsible for creating and organising a studio session for developers & designers to inspire ideas, help drive forward with new projects and create an awareness of technical advancements within the industry.

Oct 00 – Feb 05: Web Developer / Technical Administrator – Hanon Shop, Aberdeen.

Responsibilities included managing all web development on the site from specification through to implementation & delivery as well as improving functionality with new features on a regular basis. Further duties included helping integrate new technologies such as bar coding into the shop and network infrastructure. I worked on the site from its very first incarnation up until it was receiving industry acclaim in Creative Review, Maxim, GQ, ID Magazine and various other publications.

Sept 99 – Oct 00: Web Designer – Digit Ltd, Ellon

Role involved various web production tasks as well as the development of an interactive CD Catalogue and accompanying print brochure using Flash & Adobe Page Maker.

Speaking Engagements

- 2014 Conference host / Interviewer @ The Highland Fling: Sessions
- 2012 British Tech Network The Web Show (Episodes 1,3)
- 2010 Texthelp Web Accessibility Day (Glasgow)
- 2009 Opera Software @ Dundee University Talk title: Back to basics
- 2009 Texthelp Web Accessibility Day(Glasgow) Talk title: Back to basics
- 2008 Guest Judge Yahoo Hack Day @ Dundee University

Events Organised

- 2017 The Highland Fling: Sessions We're Professionalising (Event Co-Organiser)
- 2017 The Highland Fling: Sessions Professionalism (Event Co-Organiser)
- 2015 The Highland Fling: Sessions Progressive enhancement (Event Co-Organiser)
- 2014 The Highland Fling: Sessions (Event Co-Organiser)
- 2011 The Highland Fling Back to basics (Event Organiser)
- 2008 The Highland Fling The browser and beyond (Event Organiser)
- 2007 The Highland Fling Progressive Enhancement (Event Organiser)

Conferences attended

- 2016 ScotlandCSS
- 2007 BarCamp Brighton
- 2007 dConstruct
- 2007 BarCamp Scotland
- 2006 @media
- 2005 @media

Education

- 2010 Autonomy Teamsite Developer Course
- 2010 Autonomy Teamsite Administrators Course
- 2000 Advanced Photoshop Course (10 Week Course Aberdeen College)
- 2000 Beginners Photoshop (10 Week Course Aberdeen College)
- 1998 GSVQ Level 2 Information Technology

Hobbies

I am definitely a net geek that spends most of my time keeping up with RSS feeds, attending meetups and learning new techniques but when I switch off I like to spend time with my family, fly drones, make stuff with clay, snowboard, record music, skate mini ramps, watch films or play a decent game on one of my many consoles.

References *

Available on request or via recommendations on LinkedIn.